KRISHNA MOHAN KUMAR SINGH

Address: - Tea garden Namkum, Ranchi

E-mail:- krishmohan.1988@gmail.com

Contact no: - 8409859486

Objective

Seeking employment that allows me to grow professionally, while being able to utilize my skills for the betterment of the organization with the best use of my dedication, determination and resourcefulness.

CERTIFICATION PATH

LINUX: Red hat (basic knowledge.)

MCSE: Microsoft Certified system engineer

CCNA: Cisco certified Network Associate

N+ : Diploma in Networking

A+ : Diploma in hardware

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Presently working on the post of Center Manager from the period of 12th March 2018 to 27 Feb 2020. My Work Location Is Jharkhand In District Of Ranchi with R.S.W.M Ltd. (LNJ Bhilwada Group) The Project Of Deen Dayal Upadhyaya Grameen Kaushalya Yojana (DDU-GKY) Founded by MORD (Ministry Of Rural Development), Govt. of India.



Worked in skill development (DDU-GKY) sponsored by Ministry of Rural Development as State Center Manager with Matrix Clothing Pvt. Ltd. from April 2017 to March 2018.

Worked as Customer support engineer for VDA Infosolutions Pvt.Ltd at Tata group in (MPL)Maithon power Ltd from 20 Dec 2015 to 31 Dec 2016

Worked as L1 Network Engineer at Gs computel Pvt Ltd Project in Dainik bhaskar Power plant Ltd from 1st Oct, 2014 to 31 August,2015

Worked as an L1Destop engineer for blackberry software support in Vodafone Ranchi in Jharkhand from 1st April, 2012 to 30 September, 2014.

Present Responsibilities:

- Key responsibilities of center manager
- > To maintain infrastructure as per project.
- ➤ Monitoring of staffs, trainers, and trainees.
- > To make invoice and maintain documents as per project norms.
- > To maintain the quality of training
- > Steering the activities of the Training center and ensuring the efficient utilization of all Training recourses
- Responsible for the quality of the technical equipment and the Setting according to the DDU-GKY needs
- Should ensure proper and regular running of training program
- > To make Arrangements for Boarding facility At the center
- > To ensure the safe keep of infrastructure provided at the training center
- Manage documentation regarding details of beneficiaries and also other documents pertaining to financial relivance
- > Submits regular training information to project manager
- > Regularly interact with beneficiaries Motivates them and take feedback on the training
- ➤ Guide (coordinate with)the Field Mobilizer for Mobilization of Batch
- > Excellent Follow-up with Regional MIS Executives and CO-ordination with Different Teams.

Nature of duties & responsibilities:-

1- Community Mobilization through AAJIVIKA Self Help Group, Village

Organization and Cluster level Federation In Palamu ,Latehar ,gumla, chatra District & west singhbhum (Jharkhand).

- 2- Networking and Coordination with AAJIVIKA DM skills and District Unit along with Job Resource Person at Village and Panchayat Level.
- 3- Counseling provided on Livelihood and income generation.
- 4- Youth Mobilization under age 18-35 Year -Community Mobilization
- 5- Attend The Youth Mobilization Drive (YMD)
- 6- Conducted Job Fire at District Level and State level for Youth
- 7- Job Placement in Garments Industries
- 8- Networking and Coordination with Jharkhand AAJIVIKA State and District Staffs'
- 9- Reporting and Documentation
- 10- Monthly Report and quarterly Report Preparation and shared to State Government and Central Ministry of Textiles.
- 11- Advocacy with BPL& POP family for income generation.

EDUCATIONAL PROFILE

(10th) from Hansraj wadhwa high school in the year 2004 (56%)

(12th) from Jharkhand intermediate council in year2006 with commerce (54%)

Graduation (Bachelor of commerce) passed from Ranchi University in the year 2010 (50.4%)

Personal Information:

Name : - Krishna Mohan Singh

Father name : - Shambhu Singh

Date of Birth : - 14-07-1989

Sex :- Male

Nationality : - Indian

Marital status : - single

Languages Known :- English. Hindi

Permanent Address: - Tea Garden Namkum Ranchi-834010

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the above-mentioned details are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Krishna

Mohan singh